Okay, so in this video, I'm going to show you how you can set up these zombies.
All right, it is really simple, you just have to follow me step-by-step, all right?
So let's start from the first zombie, which is this one right here.
Okay, in order to set this zombie, what we're going to do is, first of all, try and drop
it right here and make sure that all of your zombies are human-oriented.
Just a reminder, then you can select this zombie, then click on, I mean, right-click,
and then click on this JUTPS create, all right, then click on Quick Setup, and then click
on JU Character, and in here, you can add this simple, third person controller, all right.
When you do that, it will show you this successful message, all right, and it will show
the successful message once your character is human or if it is not, then it will not work.
Okay, that's why, make sure your character is human-oriented and it has a avatar, all right.
When you do that, you will notice that on this, now there will be these few options, all right,
which are added.
So now this is actually a controller, a simple, third person controller, now in order
to make it a zombie, to give it the zombie AI, you will have to click on Quick Setup, add,
and then set up zombie AI, all right, when you do that, now it has the zombie AI and everything
else as well.
All right, so now we need to do a few changes, the first one will be to change the attacker
distance, so I'm just going to change this to 1.2, and then if you check the field of
view, we're going to change that to 12, and then this to 280, and you will be seeing these
values once you run on the cosmos, okay, as you can see right there, okay, this is the field
of view, that's why I made it 280, so that the zombie can detect player in this red circle
and then this is the radius, so if the player gets inside this radius, the zombie will
know that he has the player has entered, so I'm just going to leave this 12 and 280 and
the attacker distance, make sure it is 1.2, these are the three things which we need to
change in the zombie AI, now for the animator, we need to change its animator because right
now it is a third person controller animator, we need to change this to the zombie, so
if you click on this circle right here and then select animator zombie, all right, it will
now play the zombie animation, the attack and everything, all right, once you do that,
then you can go ahead and play the game, and the game start, the zombies as you can see
walking right there, moving to different points, but if you notice it is just going in circles
and also the zombie doesn't move to anywhere else, and the reason behind that is we didn't
have any nav mesh, so now before testing it out, we need to have nav mesh, I mean we need
to bake our environment, so in order to bake it, what we are going to do is click on
this environment and let's add not a nav mesh agent, actually nav mesh obstacle, all right and
for this as you can see you will have to install the AI navigation package, so if you
are seeing this button, just click it, but if you are not seeing this button, then you
can click on package, management and package manager, and in the Unity registry, right here
you can search for AI, and right here we have AI navigation, let's click on install, once
it is installed, let's click that out now, and in the environment, we have this nav mesh
obstacle, right here let's actually now remove that and nav mesh surface add that to the
environment, turn on the gizmos, so that we can see whatever is happening, and now we just
need to click on this bake, make sure the environment is selected and then the environment
had the nav mesh surface and then click bake, and now as you can see it is baking, so you
will have to wait for it, it will take few seconds or few minutes that according to your
PC, all right so let's just wait for it, and it took 10, 15 seconds and now it is baked
as you can see, you can see these blue things, now the zombie will be able to walk in this
whole environment, all right turn off the gizmos, all right and click on the zombie, on
the zombie now, we will be adding few things, for example the script call AI random destination,
make sure that you add that script to it and after that you will have to add the ju character
setting for, all to make sure that you add this script as well, and for the player controller
it will be added automatically, you just have to add this, all right, if you turn
on here it is, now the zombie will still be not able to follow the player around, so for
that you will have to click on this FPS character which is over player, okay and make sure
that on this character the nav mesh obstacle is added, okay, it will be added automatically
if you follow the same step as I did from the start of this course, it will be already
added but if it is not make sure that you add it and all of the values are same as this
and when that is added the player will be, I mean the zombie player will be able to follow
the player in the environment now, okay, so if we turn the game again click on scene
wheel, okay this is over player, this is the zombie now, as we can see the zombie can walk
around in the environment, okay, the zombie is going inside the water, but that's okay,
that's to the zombie now and see what the zombie do when it sees the player, okay, I think
the zombie move away, okay there it is, whoops, whoops, whoops, okay, now the zombie is
on the ground, if we go ahead and see the thing it is really dark, I can't see the zombie,
okay there it is, okay there is the zombie, now when the zombie sees the player as you can
see, the zombie try to run towards the player and try to attack the player, but if you
notice the zombie is unable to deal any damage to the player, because the zombie doesn't
have any hitboxes for now, don't worry we will make the zombie damage the player and
if you notice the cursor when the cursor is on the zombie it is where it means that this
is the zombie and if you notice we can deal damage to the zombie and we can kill the zombie
there it is, but if you notice the animations were a bit messed up and also as you can see
the zombie is going inside the ground, okay we will be fixing these issues as well, also
let's click on the zombie and for the area we are going to select 50 and we are going to
move the zombie in the middle, so at the zombie doesn't walk in the water, okay make sure
that you do that and if you select the zombie, okay the animator zombie controller is added,
let's also go ahead and resize its capsule color, if you check its capsule color this
zombie, okay we need to fix that, so what we are going to do is we are going to change
its radius to 1 and the height should be 1.9, alright that is it and we need to move this a little
bit up, so that covers the zombie head as well, okay so for that make it 1.1 so that
covers the zombie head like that, okay and actually let's make this 2 and make this 1.07,
oh yep 1.04, so make sure that you do all of these changes, alright and in the same way
you can go ahead and set up these other zombies as well, you can follow this video for
this other zombies now and set up them 1 by 1, alright I am going to do it in order to save
all time, because if I try to add all of this stuff it will make the video really lengthy,
so now you know how you can set up the zombie step by step and go ahead and set all
of these zombies, I know there are some issues, for example the zombie were going inside
the ground, okay and also the animation was a bit messed up, so in the upcoming videos
we are going to fix that, okay but your first kind of a homework case to set up out of
the other zombies by your own.